Namaskar Welcome to nishamadhulika.com
Today we will make neer dosa.
Neer dosa is prepared with very fine rice batter and it tastes delicious.
Let’s start with the procedure of making neer dosa.
For this we are using;
Rice – 1 cup (soaked) (uncooked)
Wash them thoroughly and soak in water. We have soaked this rice for 2-3 hours.
Coconut – 2-3 tbsp (grated) (fresh)
Refined oil – 2-3 tbsp
Salt – ½ tsp (as per taste)
Firstly prepare a very fine paste by grinding coconut and rice.
Strain rice to remove extra water.
Place the rice in mixture jar.
Also add coconut.
Ground both the ingredients together.
You also skip the use of coconut.
But coconut enhances the flavor of dosa.
Add little amount of water.
Make sure you don’t add too much of water else batter will remain thick.
Now grind it.
Batter is not yet fine as we can see coarse pieces of rice.
Grind until batter turns smooth.
Fine rice-coconut paste is now ready.
Take out the smooth batter in a bowl.
Now we will make this batter thinner as neer dosa is prepared with very thin batter.
Add salt in the batter and mix well.
Make it thinner.
It should have pouring consistency.
Keep the consistency same as required for making sooji dosa.
Now we will make dosa.
We have used 1.5 cups of water till now.
Preheat a tawa.
We have used nonstick tawa for making dosa.
Pour some oil on the tawa and spread it evenly all around with help of napkin paper or muslin cloth.
Tawa is sufficiently hot, now spread dosa over it.
Take 1 big spoon at once or 2-3 tsp batter in a bowl like this.
Keep the flame medium-high for roasting dosa.
Now pour some oil all around the dosa and cook until it turns darker on surface and little brown from beneath.
When dosa starts separating from corners then give it a fold.
Dosa has started separating from corners and within 2 minutes it got roasted from beneath.
Now fold it like this.
There is no need to roast dosa from other side as it’s very thin.
Now place the dosa on the plate.
Clean the tawa before making other dosa and reduce the flame.
Likewise prepare another dosa.
Increase the flame again and pour some oil all around the dosa.
Roast for 2-2.5minutes
If batter turns thicker then add some more water into it.
Dosa is ready, fold and place it on plate.
Likewise prepare all dosas.
All dosas are ready now and with this much quantity we have prepared eight dosas.
Soft and delicious neer dosas are ready.
Making neer dosa is very easy but keep note of few things.
The most important thing to note while making batter is that batter should be very fine and smooth.
Rice granules should not be visible.
Batter should be thinner in consistency.
Roast dosa on sufficiently hot tawa for 2-3 minutes.
Within 2-3 minutes dosa is prepared then fold it.
These dosas can be prepared very easily.
Neer dosa can be served with coconut chutney, peanut chutney or sambhar.
Prepare these dosas for breakfast, pack them in for lunch or pack in tiffin of kids.
If kids relish eating sweet, then prepare a mixture with coconut and jaggery and serve.
This will be a nutritious breakfast for them,
Try making this recipe at your home and share your experiences with nishamadhulika.com
See you soon with another new delightful recipe. Do subscribe my youtube channel as well.